N S MD Imran Zakir

Experienced Project Engineer

Hatfield, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/N-S-MD-Imran-Zakir/09f1fb78b538efbe

Pursuing a career opportunity to take challenge for any position in an organization where I can apply my education, skill and experience to get results, foster teamwork and achieve goals.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Executive Engineer

Electricity Generation Company of Bangladesh Ltd. (An enterprise of Bangladesh Power Development Board) - Dhaka - January 2006 to September 2015

Responsibilities

- Supervised overall construction activities of a 2X120MW simple cycle and a 335 MW combined cycle power plant project.
- Prepared Bid Document and conducted evaluation of both technical/financial proposals as per guideline of ADB/WB.
- Supervised implementation activity schedule submitted by EPC Contractor.
- Established Terms & Conditions of L/C in multi currencies, checked shipment documents in line with L/C and Contract.
- Checked & Certified Invoices of EPC Contractor according to progress of field work /material shipment.
- Conducted Post Landing Inspection (PLI) and prepared Receipt cum Damage Report
- Reviewed drawing, design & report submitted by the EPC Contractor following different Standards (like BS 1024, BS 3693, BS 6739, BS 759, IEC 60297, NFPA 850, etc).
- Supervised ware-house material management and ensured the storage of materials as per Preservation Method set-forth by the OEM.
- Ensured timely delivery of required materials from ware-house.
- Witnessed performance and guarantee tests of different equipment.
- Prepared various reports for donor agency (ADB/WB) & reply of EPC's letters in light of Contract. Drafted correspondences, memoranda, reports, forms, documents and requisitions.
- Maintained and fostered contacts with consultants, contractors, vendors and material suppliers.
- Witnessed FAT's (at different OEM locations like USA, Japan, India) and SAT's

Apprentice Engineer, Directorate of Project Planning

Bangladesh Power Development Board (BPDB) - Dhaka - September 2005 to December 2005

Prepared Development Project Proposal (DPP) of 2 (two) projects.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology 2000 to 2004

SKILLS

Bid Preparation, Proposal Evaluation & Contract Negotiation • Project Planning, Scope, Management & Completion •L/C dealings, shipment documents & Incoterms 2015 • Material Management, pre-shipment/post-shipment Inspection • Cost management, Payment terms/procedures • evaluate projects / proposals • MS Office & MS Project (10+ years)

LINKS

https://www.linkedin.com/pub/imran-zakir/42/b07/299

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Professional Training Obtained:

- Training on Frame 9E Gas Turbine at different OEM Works in India, conducted by Bharat Heavy Electricals Limited (BHEL). The training was comprised of Design, Assembly, Testing & Commissioning and Operation & Maintenance of Frame 9E Gas Turbine unit (45 days duration)
- Short course on Combined Cycle Gas Turbine held at Cranfield University, Bedford, United Kingdom with financial aid by World Bank.

Membership of Learned Societies, Professional Institutions:

- Member of Bangladesh Society of Mechanical Engineers (BSME)
- Member of Institute of Engineers, Bangladesh (IEB).